#### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

# Ratnesh Dubey

https://www.behance.net/Ratnesh15jun

#### **CONTACT US**



ratnesh15jun@gmail.com



0 816-084-6066



Gayatri Nagar Allapur Borabanda Hyderabad Telangana 500018

#### Skill

UI/UX design
Web design

Graphic design

User map / User journey Protyping & Wire framing

Case study

**User Interaction** 

User Research and usability testing

Agile

Information architecture HTML 5 / 4.0 CSS 3 Frontend developer

SASS JQuery

## **SOFTWARE**

Adobe XD Figma

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

CorelDraw X6

Github

Visual Studio 2013

Sketch

Adobe's Creative Cloud

#### Sr. UI Designer | UX Designer | Visua

15 years of experience in designing software products an applications in all stages and software development lifecy through quality assurance (QA) and tuning. Extensive known information architecture, web design, project management human-computer interaction (HCI), navigation, and usability production skills with emphasis on interactive elements. Experience interpersonal, and time-management skills.



#### PERSONAL INFORMATIONS

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

I'm a highly creative Front end developer with experience in both the public and private sectors. Obtain a challenging and creative position where my knowledge can be utilized for reaching the Professional growth of an organization and which in turn would help me enhance my skills and career.

#### **ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS**

2002-2005 B.Sc (Bachelor of Science)

Purvanchal University, (UP)

2005-2007 PGDIM (Post graduate Diploma Multimedia Program)

Program Web Specialization Prism Multimedia, Hyderabad, (TL)

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **UI/UX Designer Rlabs**

As a Freelance employee

Collaborate with team product managers, stakeholders and development teams to create the most usable user experience. Create dashboard and production assets for design.

Tools used: Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop

#### **UI/UX Designer Gathi Analytics**

Aug 2020 - Dec 2021

As a contract employee through Rannrise

communicate interaction and design ideas

Collaborate with product management and engineering to define and implement innovative solutions for the product direction, visuals and experience.

Execute all visual design stages from concept to final hand-off to engineering

Conceptualize original ideas that bring simplicity and user friendliness to complex design

Create wireframes, storyboards, user flows, process flows and site maps to effectively

Tools used: Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop Html, Css, JQuery and Angular.js

#### **UI/UX Designer at Techno Brain**

Jun 2019 – Jul 2020

Collaborate with a team product managers, business stakeholders and development teams to create the most usable customer experience Create production assets and design specifications for development team. Also work closely with them in implementation and development phases Designing Responsive websites with Bootstrap framework

Tools used: Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop Html, Saas Css, JQuery and Angular.js

#### Sr. UI/UX Engineer at Bharti Soft Tech

Feb 2017 - Jun 201

Worked as a UI UX engineer with Zoodel (e-Commerce website), ZoodMall (IOS and Android App), ZoodMall Pro (IOS and Android App). My role in all these is to create mockups, wireframes, high fidelity PSDs, interactive prototype and integrating the approved design in HTML and php to support all devices. I collaborated with developer teams & managed a wide variety of crossmedia projects involving branding, illustrations & UI design.

Tools used: XD, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop Html, Css, React.js, JQuery & Node.js

### **SKILLS ACQUIRED**

Eager to learn new technologies and constantly upgrade my skills

Establish and promote design guidelines, best practices and standards

Excellent visual design skills with sensitivity to user-system interaction

High level of integrity and commitment ability to work under stress

Adaptability to situations. Team building, Multi tasking Excellent analytical, design and problem solving skills.

Analysis of requirement.

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

Father Name: R.P. Dubey

Date of Birth: 15-06-1984.

Nationality: Indian

Languages : English, Marathi, Hindi

Passport No: K1736673

#### **CURRICULUM VITAE**



#### Sr. UI Developer Gateway technolabs Pvt. Ltd Aug 2013 – Feb 2017

Worked as Sr. UI/UX Developer with "HRMS and Spin" team to create useful, engaging dashboards, visualizations for various sales regions and its users and executives. Creating wireframes - low & high fidelity mock-ups Collaborate with product managers, business stakeholders and development teams to create the most usable customer experience. Clarity. In UI design, the term clarity means using recognizable features and elements that are intuitive to interact with consistency is essential in design for building trust

Tools used: XD, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, Html, SAAS, JQuery and Angular.js

#### **UI Designer Synoverge Technologies Pvt**

Jun 2010 – Jul 2013

Demonstrable UI design skills with a strong portfolio

Solid experience in creating wireframes, storyboards, user flows, process flows and site maps Proficiency in Photoshop, Illustrator, Omni Graffle, or other visual design and wire-framing tools

Proficiency in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for rapid prototyping.

Excellent visual design skills with sensitivity to user-system interaction

Ability to present your designs and sell your solutions to various stakeholders.

Ability to solve problems creatively and effectively.

Up-to-date with the latest UI trends, techniques, and technologies. BS/MS in Human-Computer Interaction, Interaction Design, or related

Tools used: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, Html, CSS, JQuery and .net

#### Jr. Designer DRDL

Aug 2008 – May 2010

contract employee through Netcom

Gathering and evaluating user requirements, in collaboration with product managers and engineers. Illustrating design ideas using storyboards, process flows and sitemaps. Designing graphic user interface elements, like menus, tabs and widgets.

Tools used: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, Html, CSS and java

#### **Projects**

#### Web url

http://belimitless.io https://ohm-energie.com/ https://www.bestdotnettraining.com https://www.squidhub.com www.shantijuniors.com http://staging-in-mgr.zoodmall.com/

www.krazymantra.com https://www.zoodel.com http://intl.zoodmall.com/int

www.pachmarhihotels.com www.flexicanbellows.com

www.deccansoft.com www.dashgo.com/login

www.glasstef.com

www.rishiexim.com www.dineshmusic.com

www.anodizefast.com www.gaiananbooks.com

www.agyield.com

http://opinionmeter.com https://www.cloud9erp.com http://synoverge.com www.hurix.com http://www.squadic.com/ www.adisongroup.com www.kishanauto.com www.chtengg.com www.csican.com www.vyaratiles.com www.smartinfosys.net www.chefsheet.com www.jitendralaces.com www.aptaindia.net www.shardaequip.com www.cremachdesigns.com www.rockvchemicals.com www.gainbuzz.com

www.getlocal.is

#### **Mobile Application url**

- 1) https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agyield&hl=en
- 2) https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pms.activity
- 3) https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.zoodel.kz
- 4) https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.hurix.kitaboo.cloudreader
- 5) https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.hurix.kitaboo.insight
- 6) https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.kwikbasket.customer